[Music]
foreign
Advanced Training so this is our ninth
YouTube video in terms of advanced level
Concepts and this is our 24th YouTube
video in terms of overall try sentence
task Concepts
so in this lesson I'm gonna teach you
how can you set a repetition
folder
level so that you can achieve some of
the automation Concepts very easily that
means you can achieve some complex test
cases or you can automate some complex
test cases very easily by using set
repetition at folder level and also I'm
gonna teach you about the result count
how we can use these result count
attribute while setting up the
repetition at folder level and then how
can we use the explicit name or a result
count as an explicit name or repetition
count as an explicit name
at test step level so basically we are
gonna automate one critical
functionality
by using set repetition
at folder level by using latest version
try sentence task
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank you
okay first let us understand
the concept of setting up repetition at
folder level
so by end of this session
you learn how to use repetition at
folder level
and we are going to add some repetition
value to a test step folder to achieve
the repetition at folder level okay
and we'll be using use the repetition
notation within a test step
so once you define the repetition value
at step folder level you are going to
use the same repetition notation
at test step level
okay so it is a parameter that allows
Tasker to repeat steps
specified number of times
so you can Define the repetition only on
test step folder level which tells Tosca
to repeat the step within the folder
okay so you can instruct task or how
many times to repeat the action
okay so we are gonna how many times that
we can achieve by using result cop okay
so now let's jump onto the system
and see one
a critical scenario are very important
scenario how can we automate by using
result count and by using set repetition
at folder level and by using explicit
name okay all these combinations by
using all these combinations we are
going to achieve the automation okay so
now let's jump out of the system
okay so this is my present Tasker latest
version okay so before we start uh
automating the scenario by using
um
the folder level repetition right so let
us understand what is the scenario that
we would like to automate and how can we
achieve that particular
automation by using folder level
repetition okay so as usual I just
landed onto I just logged into demo
webshop right on which we are working
from past a couple of uh sessions right
so and then I added a couple of products
uh like belt jeans and shoe in the
shopping cart okay so now
I want to empty this shopping cart if
you remember correctly so in my previous
session we already automated this
emptying shopping cart functionality by
using while loop okay where I have
covered concepts of while if else
conditions right okay we already
performed automation of emptying
shopping cart by using while
but in this session we are going to
automate the same scenario
by using repetition on folder level and
also by using result count
okay so how can we achieve the
automation let's
automate the scenario now okay for that
let's go back to our present stalker
navigate to exercises
and go to repetition folder under
repetition folder you have empty
shopping cart
test case which I already created okay
under this under process there is a
folder called empty shopping cart so
basically what is this test case it's
basically what it is doing it is simply
logging in
adding some products
and then
it's gonna
empty the shopping cart right
and then we are gonna log out from the
session okay
okay so once I click on this empty
shopping cart I can see there are two
steps one is I'm navigating to cart
and then updating the shopping cart that
means I'm navigating to cart once you
navigate to cut you need to check the
check box
and click on update shopping cart you
need to check all the check boxes that
are available so basically all the items
that are available in your shopping cart
and click on update shopping cart then
that will remove all of your
items from the shopping cart
so let's say you have 10 items you have
to click on this remove checkbox for the
10 items and then click on update
shopping cart which will remove all the
items from shopping cart okay so that's
what we are going to do okay for that
let's go back to empty shopping cart
folder
and then start working on this
particular folder okay
so for now let's create one additional
folder okay so let me create one
additional folder under empty shopping
cart or let me create additional
a test step
okay what the step I want to
call and sorry shopping cart
test tip so how just place on the folder
empty shopping cart folder Ctrl T and
then I'm gonna call the shopping cart
module okay
and name this shopping cart module as
verify
verify um what I'm gonna do I'm gonna
verify if the items exist in the
shopping cart or not okay
so verify
verify
table exists okay so I have to put this
into the logical order first I will be
navigating to cart so then verifying the
verifying if the shopping cart table
exists this is a table okay if the table
exists or not I'm gonna verify
and then again let me call this same
shopping cart functionality again okay
Ctrl T sorry shopping cart module
shopping cart module
and name this as
count number of
unique count number of unique
items in cart so let me name this as
count number of
unique items
in the cart
again drag and drop here so first I'm
going to verify if the table exists if
table exist how many number of items
exist in this table
okay
and then
I need to calculate so then I'm going to
create one more
test step
to set okay let me just
okay so now again let's call another
step
Ctrl T here I'm gonna set a buffer I'm
gonna set the buffer okay
buffer t-box set buffer why I'm gonna
tell you okay see when I'm actually
again drag and drop here okay so after
counting number of items here right what
it will do number of items
so sorry I think we call some wrong
table okay let's do one thing count
number of indicatives we call some wrong
uh
module here let's do
one more time Ctrl t
shopping cart
yeah shopping cart okay module
yes this is correct so let's drag
and drop here once I verify the table I
need to count the number of unique items
right number of unique items let's name
this as
count
unique
items in Cut okay once I count the
number of unit what happens right when I
count the number of
items what it will do it's going to
count the header also this is your
header
1 this is the second row 2 3 4 so that
means I have to remove the header part
basically so when I get the result count
it's going to give me
all the
table rows including header so that's
why now what I am doing here I'm gonna
calculate the
number of items
without header so that means that's why
calculate
[Applause]
items
foreign
how by using set buffer I'm gonna tell
you I'm going to populate the values
shortly okay
and then here once that is done let me
create another folder now once I
calculate now I have to start removing
the items correct so for that let me
create one folder right click
here create folder and name this as
select remove
so that means once I get it I have to
for all the items that are existing in
the shopping cart
again drag and drop here
okay
now once I select remove
now it is our time to populate all the
values now okay so now let's populate
values first
verify table exist so I want to verify
if the table exists or not correct so
what table this is the table shopping
cart table okay so for us simply
just take this as
exist
is equal to
true
okay
I am verifying if the table exists
and then here I need to select the
action mode as verify
and verifying so that is done
once I verify I need to count here let's
expand this count the number of unique
items in the cart right so for that this
is my table
correct
and this is my rows correct and under
rows I want to verify I want to
see the result count so the result count
gives you the number of
items available in this shopping cart
okay here
just put this as
result count
and I want to
name I want to calculate the number of
items and I want to store them into a
buffer called
card items card items
card items okay
and here let's
select the action mode as buffer
okay so what I am doing
number of rows whatever the result count
the result count gives me I'm storing it
into buffer
called card items
right so this gives you the number of
rows exists in the table
including the header so now it's time
for me to remove the header how let's go
to
the next test step called calculate
items
in card without header for this what I'm
going to do I'm going to create one
buffer I'm going to set the buffer
called
actual
card number what is our actual card
number my actual card number is
let me copy this buffer okay name let me
copy this muffin one my actual card
number is I need to use the math
function here
math
okay math
take the buffer that we got here above
above buffer okay what is the buffer
your cart items is your buffer correct
cart items is buffer
take that buffer
and then
enter the buffer name here okay
for that capital B buffer
sorry with curly braces capital B buffer
and then card items card item see I it
shows my card items and then close pair
braces
close the librasives now I have to
remove one because it is also
calculating the header right I want to
remove one if it if I get total number
of results count as four then I have to
remove one and your actual card items
are three
right so that's why I'm removing one
close the square braces and curly bases
so this will give you actual number of
items in the cart okay so done I
calculated that as well
now
navigate to your
select
remove folder now okay what we are going
to do
[Music]
for select remove folder
I'm gonna specify the repetition here
what repetition I'm going to specify I
am going to repeat I'm going to specify
it as my actual card number correct
so let's
specify the repetition as
let's call the buffer
what buffer the actual card number
actual card number buffer and specifying
the repetition value as the actual card
number that means I want to repeat
I want to repeat
selecting these remove check box how
many times
the number of times
I got from the actual
card number
okay so that means number of items how
many number of let's say three items
that means I need to select three times
right so I am asking to repeat this
folder see as soon as I provide some
value here the folder if you see the
repetition symbol is
shown here
okay done
now let's insert some test steps in
this particular folder okay first empty
shopping cart okay let's
again I'm gonna call this same shopping
cart see shopping cart module here and
name this as
empty
cart
okay I named this as empty cart okay so
once I click on empty cart I I mentioned
as empty card
okay here
what we need to do we have to now
empty the shopping cart so as I remember
this folder will repeat number of times
whatever we specified here okay so now
here
let's go to
your row here okay each row
here
I can do one thing okay either I can
select my first row hard coded if I
select first row what I'm going to do is
going to select here
if I select second row
if I mention as
dollar two it will select your second
item right now I don't want to do that
what I want to do I want to use the
repetition how see you need to specify
dollar
curly braces
repetition re
-t-i-t-i-o-n and close your curly braces
what it will do whatever you specified
in the repetition
so here I'm using the same explicit name
so basically this repetition can be used
as an explicit name what I am doing for
the test step itself I am changing the
name of your test step as a repetition
okay
so now expand this
and here
I need to select remove right here
you need to select remove
and then
once you select remove
here if you expand remove again here
okay so instead of verify I want to
select it as select
under remove
column so basically see Row 1
your Row 1
my columns are removed product price
quantity and total right so what I did
here I selected remove instead of
product price quantity I selected the
column called remove
under column called remove I can see the
check boxes right so these are all the
columns
for the Row 1
column remove
and here this is my checkbox so I want
to make this as
true I want to check the checkbox
and your action mode is true that means
what it will do let's say I got the
actual card number as 3.
first it comes here first it takes as
one
check the check box
again it repeats the same thing
this time it's going to take it as
number two
and then it's check the check box and
then again it's going to repeat
and at this time the column number will
be taking as three sorry the row number
will be taking as 3. so that way is
going to repeat the number of times the
actual card items present
okay
hope you all understand so there is no
confusion right so if you have any
queries you can leave your queries in
the comment box okay
so that is done
I think
we are good now okay so now let's run
this entire test case and see how it
works
okay
run this entire test case let me make
sure we achieved everything okay we are
navigating to shopping cart and we are
verifying if table exist and then we are
counting the number of rows I mean
result by using result count and we are
removing the header part header row
correct from the number of rows and then
we are selecting remove by using
repetition I'm using repetition here
I am selecting the check box
the number of times is same as your
number of items and then I am clicking
on update shopping cart see the button
called update shopping cart button after
checking all the items okay so hopefully
it should work let's log out so let me
first empty the shopping cart okay let
me empty the shopping cart
okay and then log out
and close it okay
so now let's run this now okay
right click
and click on run
scratch book run in scratchbook so it
should log in first
it should open your webshop
and then it should add some random
products to the shopping cart
and then it should remove the shopping
cart by using repetition functionality
okay
so it is logging in
once it is logging in so it's going to
go to the shopping cart and then it's
going to add some items okay it's adding
blue jeans
right to the shopping cart 25 Bridges
and then it went to jewelries and it is
adding some but Diamond Heart Right
done so now it's going to the shopping
cart and then see it checked
both the check boxes and clicked on
update shopping cart okay so if you see
here all the tests our test cases the
test case is passed so basically all the
steps are successfully completed so if
you see here if I go to select remove
folder right so if you see here the
repetition actually it is repeating
twice
see
that means it checked two times because
the shopping cart has only two items so
if your shopping cart has
uh more than two items then it's gonna
check multiple times four times okay so
hope you all understand the concept of
how to use
a repetition
at folder level repetition at folder
level
and then how can you use your result
count also right to calculate the number
of rows
and then how can you use the repetition
attribute a test step level right I
specified it as dollar repetition right
so if you have any queries leave your
queries in the comment box I'll try to
respond to your queries thank you
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank you
[Music]